https://www.smkw.com/privacy-policy

1-800-251-9306
My Account My Wish List Sign Out Sign In
My Cart
Menu KnivesFolding KnivesModern Folding KnivesEveryday Carry Folding KnivesLinerlock EDC KnivesLockback EDC KnivesFramelock EDC KnivesNon-Locking EDC KnivesButton Lock EDC KnivesMiscellaneous EDC Folding KnivesKeychain EDC KnivesSurvival EDC Folding KnivesAXIS Lock EDC KnivesAT-XRAssisted Opening KnivesButterfly KnivesFolding Hunting KnivesFolding KarambitsNautical and Rigging KnivesPocket KnivesBackpocketBarlowButterbeanCanoeCheetahCongressCopperheadCopperlockDoctors KnifeElectricianElephant ToeFolding HunterGunstockHawkbillHoboJackLady LegLobsterLockbackLockingMiscellaneous Pocket KnivesMooseMuskratPeanutPenRazorRusslockSaddlehornScoutSleeveboardSlipjoint Pocket KnivesSod BusterSowbellyStilettoStockmanStraight RazorSway Back JackSway BellyTear DropToothpickTrapperTribal LockWhittlerNovelty Folding KnivesRescue Folding KnivesFolding Utility KnivesFantasy Folding KnivesCeramic Folding KnivesEquine Folding KnivesFixed Blade KnivesEveryday Carry Fixed Blade KnivesFixed Combat KnivesTraditional Combat KnivesDaggers and Boot KnivesNeck KnivesKarambit KnivesBayonetsMauser BayonetsHunting KnivesClassic Hunting KnivesSkinning KnivesFillet KnivesMiscellaneous Fixed Blade Hunting KnivesSurvival KnivesBowie KnivesMachetesSwordsCane SwordsFantasy SwordsHistorical SwordsMiscellaneous SwordsShort SwordsSword AccessoriesTraining SwordsThrowing KnivesFixed Blade Fantasy KnivesRescue KnivesFixed Blade Training KnivesDiving KnivesLetter OpenersBelt Buckle KnivesKatanasKitchen KnivesBoning KnivesBread KnivesButcher KnivesCarving KnivesChef's KnivesCleaversCooks KnivesFillet Kitchen KnivesKitchen Knife Block SetsKitchen Utility KnivesMiscellaneous Kitchen CutleryParing KnivesSantoku KnivesSlicing KnivesSteak KnivesTomato KnivesVegetable KnivesAutomatic KnivesOut the Side Automatic KnivesOut the Front Automatic KnivesAntique and Custom KnivesAntique KnivesCustom KnivesCollectible KnivesVintage KnivesSwiss Army KnivesBantamCadetCamperCenturionChampSwissChampWorkChampMiniChampSAK CigarClassicClassic AloxClassic SDClassic LEClimberCraftsmanCyberToolElectricianEvolutionEvoWoodEvoGripExecutiveExplorerFarmerFieldMasterFishermanForesterGardenerSAK GolfToolHelmsmanHerculesHikerHunterHunter ProHunter XTHuntsmanJuniorManagerMechanicMiscellaneous Swiss Army KnivesSAK MoneyClipMountaineerSAK NailClipPioneerPocketPalRallyRamblerRangerRangerGripRangerWoodRecruitSAK Replacement PartsSAK RescueToolSignatureSignature LiteSkipperSoldierSAK SpartanSwissCardSwissLiteSwissToolTravelerTrekkerTinkerDeluxe TinkerScout TinkerSmall TinkerStandard TinkerSuper TinkerTouristWaiterKnife SetsKnives Recommended by Women for WomenTop Shelf KnivesCustom ShopKnife AccessoriesKnife SharpenersSharpening StonesArkansas StonesDiamond StonesFlat StonesPuck StonesSharpening KitsKit PartsPull-Through SharpenersElectric Pull-Through SharpenersPocket SharpenersFlip OutKeychainSharpening RodsSharpening FilesBelt SharpenersReplacement BeltsStropsKnife PartsBlade BlanksBlade GuardsButt CapsHandlesMiscellaneous Knife PartsRivetsSpacersSheathsLeather SheathsMolded SheathsNylon SheathsMiscellaneous SheathsDisplay CasesKnife RollsHonesOilPasteMiscellaneous Knife AccessoriesNew ArrivalsFlash SaleExclusivesMore StuffApparelApparel AccessoriesBelt BucklesHat PinsMiscellaneous Apparel AccessoriesMoney ClipsParacord BraceletsPatchesStrapsClothingPantsShirtsHatsFootwearShortsJacketsMiscellaneous ClothingSocksHunting ApparelFishing ApparelCamping ApparelGearBagsBeltsMiscellaneous GearPouchesSunglassesWatchesVestsBranded GearGiftsSignsGifts for DadKnives for DadGear for DadTools for DadStuff for DadGiftcardsRelicsArrowheadsFossilsMiscellaneous RelicsReplicasShaving GiftsBooksInstructional BooksMilitary BooksMiscellaneous BooksMiscellaneous GiftsVideosHousewaresKitchenwareKitchen AccessoriesKitchen Knife BlocksKitchen Knife SharpenersMiscellaneous Kitchen AccessoriesKitchen GadgetsSporting GoodsFirearm AccessoriesHolstersGun Cleaning SuppliesPistol GripsGun CasesGun MagazinesHigh Capacity Gun MagazinesMiscellaneous Firearm AccessoriesGun SlingsTargetsRifle Scopes and SightsRifle StocksMartial ArtsBo StaffNunchakuMiscellaneous Martial Arts ProductsSaiThrowing StarsMartial Arts Training ProductsKubatonsMilitary SurplusCanteenGas MasksHelmetsMiscellaneous Military SurplusUtensilsOutdoorsBB GunsBinocularsBlowgunsCamping SuppliesHunting SuppliesFishing SuppliesMedical KitsMiscellaneous Outdoor SuppliesParacordSlingshotsCoolersSelf DefenseCanesDefense ToolsHandcuffsMiscellaneous Self Defense ProductsPepper SprayStungunsTactical PensBlackpowder Cap & BallToolsAxesFantasy AxesMiscellaneous AxesTactical AxesThrowing AxesTraditional AxesFlashlightsFlashlight AccessoriesBatteriesFlashlight SheathsGun Mounted FlashlightsHeadlampsLanternsMiscellaneous FlashlightsTactical FlashlightsLightersLighter SheathsMulti-toolsMiscellaneous ToolsRescue ToolsSawsScrewdriversShearsShovelsSpearsSpearheads and ArrowheadsWood Carving ToolsComing SoonAmmoHandgun AmmoRifle AmmoRimfire AmmoShotgun Ammo350 LegendBrands
Account
Home
Privacy Policy
Customer Service
FAQS
Shipping and Handling
Product Disclaimer
Privacy Policy
Smoky Mountain Knife Works is dedicated to making its website, www.smkw.com, a safe and secure place for our customers to shop. To that end, we have developed a privacy policy with the concerns of our customer in mind. Smoky Mountain Knife Works takes the privacy of our customers and the security of their Personal Information very seriously.
SMKW.com Privacy Policy
This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for www.smkw.com This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site. It will notify you of the following:
What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.
What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.
The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.
How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
Information Collection, Use, and Sharing
1) Data you provide to us
When you create an account, signup for our newsletter, signup for an in-stock notification, or submit info to us using social media or a 3rd party app you are asked to provide personal information that uniquely identifies you.
We collect the following types of personal information: your contact information (such as name, postal or email address, or phone number), birthdate, name, username and password, shipping information (including the shipping address and phone number), purchase history, shopping preferences (such as an interest in a particular product category), information you provide by interacting with us through social media, and photographs that you submit through our social media channels. If you do post personal information via social media or on a product review, you do so at your own risk, as we cannot control who may see this information.
You don't have to provide any information that directly identifies you to browse our website. However, we will ask you to provide certain personal information as necessary to provide you with requested products and services, complete the relevant transaction, or, if you wish, use special features or functions of our website. We will share this personal information with companies we partner with to better enhance your experience on our site, including but not limited to payment processing, our own email marketing campaigns, fraud prevention services, etc.
2) Data we automatically collect
We and select businesses with whose technology we use on the site, use technologies such as cookies, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users' movements around the website, and to gather non-sensitive demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies on an individual or aggregate basis. Further information is contained below.
Analytics & Log Files. As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. When you visit our websites, we automatically collect the following types of information: information about the device you use to access the Internet (such as the internet protocol (IP) address, internet service provider (ISP) or mobile carrier, proxy server, device type, browser and add-ons, and operating system), referring/exit pages, date/time stamps, information on your shopping behavior on our website (e.g., page views, paths you take through our websites, etc.), general geographic location information (e.g., country or city) that shows where you are when browsing our websites, and search terms that you enter to reach our websites or enter on our websites to find products. We utilize analytics services and log files to help us track the efficacy of our websites, help us learn more about our customers' and visitors' shopping behavior, and for troubleshooting and maintenance purposes. We may collect and summarize customer and visitor information in a non-personal format for statistical and research purposes.
Cookies, and Other Similar Technologies. We use cookies and similar technologies to recognize you and/or your device(s) on, off and across different services and devices.
a) Cookies. We automatically collect anonymous information through cookies. Cookies are small text files stored by your Web browser on your computer, phone, tablet, or other device used to browse our site. Cookies allow us to identify and authenticate visitors, track behavior, and enable important site features. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. The persistent cookie maintains your login information so that your cart and login remain available when you return to the site. Session cookies are used to maintain your shopping state as you browse through the site. YouTube uses cookies to help maintain the integrity of video statistics, prevent fraud and to improve the site experience, among other things. We also contract with analytics services and third-party advertising companies to collect similar information for specific purposes. The use of cookies by our partners is not covered by this policy.
b) Social Media Features. Our site includes social media features, such as the Facebook "Like" button and widgets, the "share this" widget, and features within our product review platform. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.
Your Access to and Control Over Information
You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via help@smkw.com with the subject line "Attention Webmaster My Data".
• See what data we have about you, if any.
• Change/correct any data we have about you.
• Have us delete any data we have about you.
• Express any concern you have about our use of your data.
Security
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.
Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed green lock icon in the address bar, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.
While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.
Orders
We request information from you on our order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (like name and shipping address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll use this information to contact you.
Credit Save Feature
No credit card info is saved on our site, instead, our credit card processor creates a profile/token for your info, which is encrypted and stored on their servers, and the only info that passes to us the token. SMKW.com does not save or have access to your credit card info. We offer this option to give you the convenience of not having to re-enter your personal data every time you shop from us.
CCPA
CA Residents: Right to deletion: You may request via an email to help@smkw.com with the subject "Attention Webmaster Delete My Data" that we delete any information we collect, however, we cannot delete info tied to purchases made for recordkeeping and financial purposes. Right to be informed: We collect several types of info via account creation and ordering which include name, phone #, address, IP address, and email address. None of this info is sold, though limited amounts of this data (email address, items purchased) are shared with partners for functions on the site such as product reviews and cart abandonment. We also collect email addresses, location, and behavior data via cookies which are analyzed by us and partners for retargeting and other SMKW marketing efforts. Right to Opt-Out: We do not offer the ability to opt-out of your info being sold, because we do not sell your info. Right of Access: To see what information we have collected about you, you can email us at help@smkw.com with the subject line "Attention Webmaster My Data" and ask for any information we might have saved, how we obtained it, what we saved it for, and who we shared it with. Alternatively, you may call us at 1-800-327-5871 and make the same request.
GDPR
EU Citizens: Right to Access and/or Take Your Data: you may contact us at help@smkw.com with the subject line "Attention Webmaster My Data" to request a copy of your personal data and can ask for a copy of personal data. You can also ask to review any of the information that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting us.
Updates
Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and all updates will be posted on this page. Last updated 1/2/2020.
